- 在本视频中，我们将研究解码器架构。
- In this video, we'll study the decoder architecture.
一个例子
An example
一种流行的解码器唯一架构是 GPT 两种。
of a popular decoder only architecture is GPT two.
为了了解解码器的工作原理
In order to understand how decoders work
我们建议你观看有关编码器的视频。
we recommend taking a look at the video regarding encoders.
它们与解码器极为相似。
They're extremely similar to decoders.
可以使用解码器
One can use a decoder
对于大多数与编码器相同的任务
for most of the same tasks as an encoder
尽管通常会有一点性能损失。
albeit with generally a little loss of performance.
让我们采用相同的方法
Let's take the same approach we have taken
用编码器试试
with the encoder to try
并了解架构差异
and understand the architectural differences
在编码器和解码器之间。
between an encoder and decoder.
我们将使用一个使用三个词的小例子。
We'll use a small example using three words.
我们通过他们的解码器传递它们。
We pass them through their decoder.
我们检索每个单词的数字表示。
We retrieve a numerical representation for each word.
这里举例来说，解码器对三个词进行转换。
Here for example, the decoder converts the three words.
欢迎来到纽约，欢迎来到这三个数字序列。
Welcome to NYC, and these three sequences of numbers.
解码器只输出一个序列
The decoder outputs exactly one sequence
每个输入词的数字。
of numbers per input word.
这个数值表示也可以
This numerical representation can also
称为特征向量或特征传感器。
be called a feature vector or a feature sensor.
让我们深入了解这种表现形式。
Let's dive in this representation.
它包含一个向量
It contains one vector
每个通过解码器的单词。
per word that was passed through the decoder.
这些向量中的每一个都是一个数字表示
Each of these vectors is a numerical representation
有问题的词。
of the word in question.
该向量的维度被定义
The dimension of that vector is defined
通过模型的架构。
by the architecture of the model.
解码器与编码器的主要区别在于
Where the decoder differs from the encoder is principally
具有自我注意机制。
with its self attention mechanism.
它使用所谓的掩蔽自我关注。
It's using what is called masked self attention.
例如，在这里，如果我们关注 “to” 这个词
Here, for example, if we focus on the word "to"
我们会看到 vector 是绝对未修改的
we'll see that is vector is absolutely unmodified
用纽约的话来说。
by the NYC word.
那是因为右边所有的话，也都知道
That's because all the words on the right, also known
因为这个词的正确上下文被掩盖了
as the right context of the word is masked rather
而不是受益于左右所有的话。
than benefiting from all the words on the left and right.
所以双向上下文。
So the bidirectional context.
解码器只能访问一个上下文
Decoders only have access to a single context
可以是左上下文或右上下文。
which can be the left context or the right context.
Masked self attention 机制不同
The masked self attention mechanism differs
来自 self attention 机制
from the self attention mechanism
通过使用额外的掩码来隐藏上下文
by using an additional mask to hide the context
在单词的两边
on either side of the word
单词数值表示不会受到影响
the words numerical representation will not be affected
通过隐藏上下文中的单词。
by the words in the hidden context.
那么什么时候应该使用解码器呢？
So when should one use a decoder?
像编码器这样的解码器可以用作独立模型
Decoders like encoders can be used as standalone models
因为它们生成数字表示。
as they generate a numerical representation.
它们还可以用于各种各样的任务。
They can also be used in a wide variety of tasks.
然而，解码器的力量在于方式。
However, the strength of a decoder lies in the way.
一个词只能访问其左侧上下文
A word can only have access to its left context
只能访问他们的左上下文。
having only access to their left context.
他们天生擅长文本生成
They're inherently good at text generation
生成单词的能力
the ability to generate a word
或给定已知单词序列的单词序列。
or a sequence of words given a known sequence of words.
这是众所周知的
This is known
作为因果语言建模或自然语言生成。
as causal language modeling or natural language generation.
这是因果语言建模如何工作的示例。
Here's an example of how causal language modeling works.
我们从一个词开始，这是我的
We start with an initial word, which is my
我们将其用作解码器的输入。
we use this as input for the decoder.
该模型输出一个数字向量
The model outputs a vector of numbers
这个向量包含有关序列的信息
and this vector contains information about the sequence
这是一个词。
which is here a single word.
我们应用一个小的转换
We apply a small transformation
到那个向量，以便它映射
to that vector so that it maps
到模型已知的所有单词，这是一个映射
to all the words known by the model, which is a mapping
我们稍后会看到称为语言建模头。
that we'll see later called a language modeling head.
我们确定该模型相信
We identify that the model believes
最有可能的后续单词是 name。
that the most probable following word is name.
然后我们取那个新词并添加它
We then take that new word and add it
到我的初始序列，我们现在以我的名字命名。
to the initial sequence from my, we are now at my name.
这就是自回归方面的用武之地。
This is where the auto regressive aspect comes in.
自回归模型。
Auto regressive models.
我们使用他们过去的输出作为输入和以下步骤。
We use their past outputs as inputs and the following steps.
我们再次执行完全相同的操作。
Once again, we do the exact same operation.
我们通过解码器投射那个序列
We cast that sequence through the decoder
并检索最有可能的后续词。
and retrieve the most probable following word.
本例中就是 “是” 这个词，我们重复操作
In this case, it is the word "is", we repeat the operation
直到我们满意为止，从一个词开始。
until we're satisfied, starting from a single word.
我们现在已经生成了一个完整的句子。
We've now generated a full sentence.
我们决定就此打住，但我们可以继续一段时间。
We decide to stop there, but we could continue for a while.
例如，GPT 2 的最大上下文大小为 1,024。
GPT two, for example, has a maximum context size of 1,024.
我们最终可以生成多达 1,024 个单词
We could eventually generate up to a 1,024 words
并且解码器仍然会有一些记忆
and the decoder would still have some memory
这个序列中的第一个单词。
of the first words in this sequence.